David Dahl

SUMMARY

Long time HTML superfan, python *nerd* and node.js *enthusiast*, I have worked as a developer, engineering manager, researcher and fundraiser - at micro and macro scales. I am a pragmatic engineer with many years of experience working with the best and brightest in the software industry

WORK EXPERIENCE

IBM https://ibm.com (Durham, NC)

Software Engineering Researcher, 2017 - present

- ► As a member of the Web Platform team, I design and implement scalable tools to help IBM with web security, privacy, internal tooling and web standards
- ▶ Designed and implemented enterprise-capable GDPR tracking tool which surfaces compliance status to management
- ► Currently building systems with Python / Django / PostgreSQL and Node.js

Advisory Software Engineer, 2016 - 2017

- ▶ I advised teams and wrote code for the IBM Marketplace
- ► Software stack was largely node.js, React, NoSQL
- ► Helped build IBM.com search UI with SearchKit, TypeScript and React

SpiderOak https://spideroak.com (Chicago, IL)

Director, Crypton project, 2013 - 2016

- Directed an engineering team building a privacy framework for mobile devices
- ► Helped raise a round of funding (\$2 MM) to continue the Crypton project
- ► Wrote code in the Crypton framework (Node.js, PostgreSQL)
- ▶ Built Kloak private social network application for iOS and Android

Mozilla Corporation https://mozilla.org (Mountain View, CA)

Senior Software Engineer, Privacy, 2012 - 2013

- ▶ Worked on new and existing browser features and WebAPIs to increase user privacy
- Engineer on Firefox OS user privileges code
- ► Worked on implementing DOMCrypt in Gecko/Firefox, which was an initial strawman proposal for the W3C Web Cryptography Working Group
- ▶ Implemented window.crypto.getRandomValues in Firefox, https://mzl.la/2JhP0JO

Firefox Engineer, 2009 - 2012

- ► Created front-end browser features, developer tools, identity APIs
- ▶ Implemented the original Web Console developer tool, https://mzl.la/2JrzPBg
- ▶ Wrote Web Console frontend and backend code

Industrial Light + Magic https://ilm.com (San Francisco, CA)

Software Engineer, 2007 - 2008

▶ ILM training department. Built Python / Django / ffmpeg-based tools for training artists, software engineers and other technical staff at ILM, LucasArts, Lucas Animation and Lucasfilm with a userbase of 1000

DAVID DAHL, PAGE 2

EDUCATION

Self-taught engineer

I have many mentors at ILM, Mozilla, Google, Facebook and IBM to be thankful for

SKILLS

Expert with Linux, Python, JavaScript, CSS, HTML, SQL, automated testing

Node, Express, npm & yarn, webpack, TypeScript, React, Django

Postgresql (including replication), MySQL, SQLite, Redis

PhoneGap / Cordova, CouchDB / Cloudant

Evaluation and recommendations for technology, teams, business processes

Very Experienced with:

C, C++, make, Android toolchain, iOS toolchain, build process

Hobby programming with:

Raspberry Pi, hardware sensors, etc. https://github.com/daviddahl/radar

TALKS / WRITING / TEACHING

Defcon 23: Crypto Village: Anti-social Networking

- ► Presentation on the Kloak application I implemented that functions like Twitter but is **end to end encrypted**
- ► https://bit.ly/2JoSNbu

Future Insights Live: Privacy is a UX Problem

- Privacy is not simply a technical issue. More designers are needed to solve privacy application issues
- ► https://bit.ly/2Jr80Jd

Hack in the Box Malaysia: Crypton Workshop

- ► https://bit.ly/2JaB2JC
- Live-coding workshop on Crypton

Crypton Whitepaper

- ▶ Crypton paper produced for Hack In The Box conference
- ► https://bit.ly/2Jbubjg

Kloak Private Social Networking Application: Slides

- ▶ Produced for Investors and Management
- https://bit.ly/2sorG6P

Cato Institute: "NSA Surveillance: What We Know; What to Do About It"

- ► Sat on the technology panel
- ► https://bit.ly/2xO8IAS

LINKS

Website

► https://txt.ist

Github

► https://github.com/daviddahl/

Latest Résumé

▶ https://txt.ist/David Dahl resume.pdf